<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:fh="http://purl.org/syndication/history/1.0" xml:base="/feed.atom" xml:lang="en">
<title>My Adventure Blog</title>
<id>https://ryanmontville.com/disney/</id>
<link rel="alternate" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/"/>
<link rel="hub" href="https://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/"/>
<link rel="self" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/feed-0.atom"/>
<link rel="first" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/feed-0.atom"/>
<link rel="current" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/feed-0.atom"/>
<link rel="next" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/feed-1.atom"/>
<link rel="last" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/feed-4.atom"/>
<updated>2025-05-16T23:04:16-04:00</updated>
<author>
<name>Ryan Montville</name>
</author>
<entry>
<title>Day 1: Move-in</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/day-1"/>
<id>https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/day-1</id>
<published>2015-01-19T00:00:00Z</published>
<updated>2015-01-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
<category term="dcp15"/><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After a 2 day, 15 hour drive, I'm finally in Orlando. This morning I went through the check-in process which took about an hour, then moved into our apartment, and then met all 5 of my roommates: Tyler, Justin, Matt, Josh, and Alex. We're living in Chatham Square in a 3 bedroom apartment, which was our first choice and the apartment is really nice.</p><p>I also found out where I was working today. I got placed at the Columbia Harbor House in the Magic Kingdom. So I'll be serving fish and chips all day long. Tomorrow is casting. Traditions is on Friday.</p>]]></content>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Day 2: Casting</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/day-2"/>
<id>https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/day-2</id>
<published>2015-01-20T00:00:00Z</published>
<updated>2015-01-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
<category term="dcp15"/><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today was casting. All of my roommates had different times than me, which is going to happen for the rest of the program since we are all working different roles. At casting they took my fingerprints and info for a background check, filled out my I-9, and got my training schedule. I have traditions Friday afternoon, and then have orientation and training for the Columbia Harbor House Sunday, Monday, and Wednesday. Later in the day we met up with some of our neighbors and went to Downtown Disney. We just walked around for awhile looking at everything. Our discounts start after Traditions, which is on Friday, so we haven't bought anything yet.</p>]]><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/01/jancasting.jpg" alt="Casting group photo"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/01/jandtd.jpg" alt="Hanging out at Downtown Disney"/></content>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Day 3: Housing orientation</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/day-3"/>
<id>https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/day-3</id>
<published>2015-01-21T00:00:00Z</published>
<updated>2015-01-21T00:00:00Z</updated>
<category term="dcp15"/><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today was the housing orientation. All of my roommates had orientation at 11, I have it at 1. After the orientation we went over to Mickey's Retreat to check it out, then back to our pool at Chatham to hang out.</p><p> Later in the day we went over to the Contemporary resort to check out where Josh is going to work as a bell hop. There are no buses that take you from one resort to another, so we took a monorail to the transportation center, then a monorail to Epcot, then a bus to the Caribbean Beach resort to check out where Alex will be working at the front desk. Then we took a bus to Downtown Disney to get another bus to the Boardwalk. There we walked around and hung out.</p>]]></content>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Day 4: Welcome event</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/day-4"/>
<id>https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/day-4</id>
<published>2015-01-22T00:00:00Z</published>
<updated>2015-01-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
<category term="dcp15"/><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today was a laid back day for us. Everyone besides Matt had the day off, he had traditions. Tonight there was a welcome party that was 20s themed which was a lot of fun. We took pictures with dapper Mickey, Minnie, and Goofy. There was free pizza and drinks. Then we danced for the rest of the party.</p>]]><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/01/jan20s.jpg" alt="Welcome event"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/01/jan20s2.jpg" alt="Welcome event"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/01/jan20s3.png" alt="Welcome event"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/01/jan20s4.png" alt="Welcome event"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/01/jan20s5.jpg" alt="Welcome event"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/01/jan20s6.jpeg" alt="Welcome event"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/01/jan20s7.png" alt="Welcome event"/></content>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Day 5: Traditions</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/day-5"/>
<id>https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/day-5</id>
<published>2015-01-23T00:00:00Z</published>
<updated>2015-01-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
<category term="dcp15"/><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today Josh, Justin, and Alex had traditions in the morning while I had traditions in the afternoon. Tyler has traditions tomorrow morning. We are able to get into the parks for free after traditions, so Alex, Josh, and Justin all went to Hollywood Studios while I went to traditions. Traditions teaches you about the Walt Disney company, the Disney story, and the goals of the company and its cast members. At traditions I received my cast member name tag and a pair of Mickey ears. We got to walk through the utilidoors, the tunnel system at the Magic Kingdom. Most people who know about the tunnels assume they are underground, but the tunnels are actually at ground level and the Magic Kingdom is on the second story. It was cool to see behind the scenes of Disney and how the Magic Kingdom operates. Soon I will be walking through the utilidoors to go to work each day at Columbia Harbor House. I got out of traditions around 7:30, which was too late to go home, eat, and then go to Magic Kingdom before it closes at 9.</p>]]><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/01/nametag.png" alt="My nametag"/></content>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Week 2: Training</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/week-2"/>
<id>https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/week-2</id>
<published>2015-01-31T00:00:00Z</published>
<updated>2015-01-31T00:00:00Z</updated>
<category term="dcp15"/><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Monday was the last day of training and my assessment to see if I knew everything about working front of house at Columbia Harbor House. I am now officially a Shipmate of the Columbia Harbor House!</p><p> Tuesday I had the day off, so I went to Epcot with Josh and Alex. We then went over to Hollywood Studios to Watch Lights, Motor, Action in the V.I.P. seats, which we were able to get because Tyler works at the show. Afterwards Tyler joined us and we hung out in the park until close. Then we went to Downtown Disney to go bowling at Splitsville. Wednesday we went back to Hollywood studios to ride some of the other rides.</p><p> Thursday was my first shift at Columbia Harbor House. I was on dining room the entire shift, which means taking out the trash, cleaning off the tables, sweeping the floors, and taking the trays to the back. Thursday was slow because it rained most of the day. The shift went well and I almost got out on time. There was a new group of college program trainees who were working dining room with me, so it took longer then normal. Friday I was on counter, greeter, and dining room. It was nice to rotate different positions instead of being in the same spot all day long. Friday was a lot busier than Thursday, which meant I always had something to do and I was never bored. I started on counter, then went to greeter, then to dining room until close. Saturday was another busy day. I once again started on counter, then moved to dining room, then back to counter to close.</p>]]><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/01/chh-costume.jpg" alt="Columbia Harbor House costume"/></content>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Week 3: After Training</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/week-3"/>
<id>https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/week-3</id>
<published>2015-02-07T00:00:00Z</published>
<updated>2015-02-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
<category term="dcp15"/><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have been training this entire week. Sunday was welcome to operations, where I learned about guest interactions and safety. Monday was welcome to food and beverage, Where I learned how to serve the food to guests. On Wednesday we walked through Magic Kingdom to learn about the history of all the lands and learn where everything is in the park. I learned several interesting facts about Liberty Square, which is where Columbia Harbor House is located. The Liberty bell in Liberty Square was made from the same mold as the original Liberty Bell. The Hall of Presidents has one of the three presidential seal in the country, which gets cleaned periodically by White House staff members. The Liberty Tree contains lanterns from the 13 original colonies. I also got my costume on Wednesday. Thursday, Friday, and Saturday was on the job training at the Columbia Harbor House. I learned all of the front of house positions including greeter, busser, and counter.</p>]]></content>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Week 4: Bad Luck</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/week-4"/>
<id>https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/week-4</id>
<published>2015-02-14T00:00:00Z</published>
<updated>2015-02-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
<category term="dcp15"/><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had a lot of bad luck this week. I drove to work for the first time on Sunday and as I was coming home from work, my car died on me. I had it towed Monday, and found out both the alternator and the battery needed replaced, which cost $750. Tuesday was supposed to be the first class of Marketing You, a class that Disney offered through the college program, but I found out it was cancelled and everyone was dropped from the class because the professor was no longer able to teach the course. Unfortunately all of the others classes are full, so I am not taking any classes offered by Disney. Wednesday night I dropped my phone and the screen cracked. I got a replacement phone through our insurance plan, but its not the same phone. On Friday I got sick and left work early. Saturday was the longest shift that I have worked so far. I started at noon and got out at midnight.</p><p> I closed everyday this week, and almost every shift was bussing tables and taking out the trash. Every shift so far has been a closing shift. Next week I have a few shift where I get out before closing. I had Monday, Tuesday, and Wednesday off this week. On Tuesday and Wednesday I went to Magic Kingdom. </p>]]></content>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>What have I done the past two weeks?</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/what-have-i-done"/>
<id>https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/what-have-i-done</id>
<published>2015-02-28T00:00:00Z</published>
<updated>2015-02-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
<category term="dcp15"/><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last week, February 15-21, was uneventful. I worked normal shifts Sunday and Monday. Tuesday I had the day off and went to Universal Studios with some friends, but it started raining so we did not do much at the park. Wednesday I did a few errands and relaxed at the apartment. Thursday through Saturday I worked.</p><p> This past week I worked Sunday, Monday, and Tuesday. Nothing interesting happened at work. Wednesday I went to Epcot with some of my roommates and meet Pluto, Mickey, Goofy, Minnie, Chip, and Dale. We also went on a few rides. My Family flew in from Ohio to visit me Wednesday night. We went to downtown Disney to go to the Rainforest Cafe and walked around for a few hours. Thursday we went to Universal Studios to go to the new Harry Potter World. Friday we went to Hollywood Studios in the morning and then to Magic Kingdom in the afternoon until park close at midnight. Saturday we went back to Universal Studios to ride the rest of the rides we didn't ride on Thursday. My Family's flight back to Ohio leaves Sunday Morning.</p>]]><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/02/febcad.jpeg" alt="Chip & Dale"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/02/febcad2.jpeg" alt="Chip & Dale"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/02/febgoofy.jpeg" alt="Goofy"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/02/febmickey.jpeg" alt="Mickey"/></content>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Week 7</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/week-7"/>
<id>https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/week-7</id>
<published>2015-03-07T00:00:00Z</published>
<updated>2015-03-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
<category term="dcp15"/><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week was pretty normal. Sunday and Monday I worked at the Harbor House. Tuesday I went to Hollywood Studios to meet Baymax and ride some rides. Later in the day I meet up with some of my roommates and we went to the Animation Academy class where we learned how to draw Stich. I also applied to extend my program  on Tuesday. Right now my program ends May 15, but if Disney approves my extension, I will be here until July 30. The weather Wednesday was great so we went to Typhoon Lagoon which was a lot of fun. Thursday, Friday, and Saturday I worked some more shifts.</p>]]><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/03/marbaymax.jpg" alt="Baymax and Hiro"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/03/marstich.jpg" alt="My attempt at drawing Stitch"/></content>
</entry>
