<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:fh="http://purl.org/syndication/history/1.0" xml:base="/feed.atom" xml:lang="en">
<title>My Adventure Blog</title>
<id>https://ryanmontville.com/disney/</id>
<link rel="alternate" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/"/>
<link rel="hub" href="https://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/"/>
<link rel="self" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/feed.atom"/>
<link rel="first" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/feed.atom"/>
<link rel="prev-archive" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/feed-2.atom"/>
<link rel="current" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/feed-3.atom"/>
<link rel="next" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/feed-4.atom"/>
<link rel="last" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/feed-4.atom"/>
<updated>2025-05-16T23:04:16-04:00</updated>
<author>
<name>Ryan Montville</name>
</author>
<entry>
<title>Working in Tomorrowland</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/tomorrowland"/>
<id>https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/tomorrowland</id>
<published>2016-08-03T00:00:00Z</published>
<updated>2016-08-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
<category term="dcp16"/><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last week I picked up a shift in Tomorrowland zone 2, which includes the Space Mountain gift shop, Ursa's Major Minor Mart, the Buzz Lightyear's Space Ranger Spin gift shop, and Buzz's Star Command cart. Tomorrowland is probably my favorite land in the Magic Kingdom, so getting to work there was a lot of fun. I spent most of the shift in the Space Mountain gift shop. One thing that Space Mountain has that we don't have at Hollywood Studios is D-Tech on Demand, where you can personalize phone cases and MagicBands. I learned how the whole process works and how to ring up guests after they have created their customized cases or bands. Another thing we don't have at Hollywood Studios is PinQuest, which is a scavenger hunt at Magic Kingdom where you can purchase clues to find pins throughout the park. Space Mountain was one of the locations of PinQuest and I was able to be apart of PinQuest by selling guests the clues and giving them the pins if they found the correct answer.</p><p>I also worked at Ursa's Major Minor Mart, which is the pin cart in front of Space Mountain, which is also near the Incredible's Super Dance Party. It was nice to hear a different set of songs besides the 14 Aerosmith songs on repeat or the same Disney covers that play every night at Fantasmic. Ursa's cart is very similar to the cart in the Rock 'n' Roller Coaster courtyard. It has trading pins, sunglasses and a glow cart. It was slow at Ursa's, but I got to enjoy Tomorrowland and the Incredible's dance party, so it was still enjoyable.</p>]]><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/07/Tomorrowland-costume.jpg" alt="Tomorrowland merchandise costume"/></content>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Working at the Emporium</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/emporium"/>
<id>https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/emporium</id>
<published>2016-08-24T00:00:00Z</published>
<updated>2016-08-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
<category term="dcp16"/><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last Friday and Saturday I worked at the Emporium in Magic Kingdom. When I clocked in on Thursday I was given a tour of the 7 zones and 5 stockrooms of the Emporium. It was a lot to take in compared to Coaster's and Tower's gift shops. At Coaster and Tower we have 3 gift registers and 2-3 photo registers while the Emporium has 35 registers.</p><p>On Friday I worked in the Mickey/Minnie room and the infants section. Working in the Mickey/Minnie room was really fun because the Emporium had already put out the Halloween merchandise in that room. While you don't have to buy merchandise items from the room they are from, most guest purchase the items near where they got them from. The Mickey/Minnie room is almost in the middle of the Emporium, so there was a fairly wide variety of the merchandise purchased. I the moved to the infants section, which is at the end of the Emporium next to Casey's Corner, making it the slowest register in the Emporium. Almost all of the guest that I rung up in the infants section were only purchasing infant merchandise. Most guests just passed through the infants section, especially after Wishes and the Main Street Electrical Parade because cast members direct them through the Emporium to reduce the crowds on Main Street. There is also a strong smell of ketchup in the infants section from Casey's, which I did not enjoy. I eventually went back to the Mickey/Minnie room and stayed there until the end of my shift. It never got too busy at any of the registers I worked at on Thursday, which made for a great first shift at the Emporium.</p><p>On Saturday my first assignment was the infants section. The start of my shift was even slower than Friday's shift, and I did not ring up many guests. I was then moved to the toys/plush section, which was much faster pace than the infants section. The toys/plush section is next the Mickey/Minnie room, so there was a wide range of items purchased, just like the registers in the Mickey/Minnie room. I was able to listen to the Main Street Electrical Parade while working in the toys/plush section and was even able to see parts of the floats through the doorways, which was awesome because I love the Electrical Parade and its soundtrack.My final assignment was the home decor section. Working in the home decor section was almost nothing but ringing up and wrapping mugs. It was also the busiest register I worked at the Emporium. After Wishes there was almost always a constant line at my register for the rest of the night. The home decor register was busier than any register at Coaster or Tower. Sometimes Fantasmic can be as busy, but only for about 5-10 minutes right before the show starts. The home decor register was busy all night.</p><p>I enjoyed working at the Emporium a lot and will definitely be picking up more shifts there, maybe even on a Mickey's Not So Scary Halloween Party night. The Emporium is probably my favorite costume to wear because the costume actually fits me unlike Coaster or Fantasmic's costume.</p>]]><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/11/main-street-costume.jpg" alt="Main Street merchandise costume"/></content>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Working at Tatooine Traders</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/tatooine-traders"/>
<id>https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/tatooine-traders</id>
<published>2016-09-19T00:00:00Z</published>
<updated>2016-09-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
<category term="dcp16"/><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last week I picked up a shift at Tatooine Traders, the Star Tours gift shop. It was weird working on the other side of Hollywood Studios. I got completely lost on my way to Tatooine Traders, and had to ask multiple people which way to go. I like my side of the park better. When I finally found where to go and clocked in, the first position I was given was the droid factory, where you can build your own droid. My job was to make sure the station was neat and organized and had enough parts. I also helped guests with any questions they had and even helped them dig though all the parts to find a specific colored piece.</p><p>There are two sets of registers in the store. The registers on the left side are called the Jawa registers and the ones on the right side are called the Death Star registers. I first worked on the Jawa registers, which have all of the expensive signed photos, jewelry, and collectibles. I then went to the Death Star registers which are beside the build your own lighsaber station. I did not have many transaction on either register.</p><p>I was able to work at the build your own lightsaber station for a little bit, which was a ton of fun. I helped the guests decide which lightsaber they wanted to build and started the saber for them by assembling the color saber they want and the hilt they wanted. After that, they moved down the line where they could pick out which covers and slides they wanted on the saber.</p><p>The one part of working in Tatooine that I did not like was that the layout of the store is so compact and has so litle room for guests, that it was always very packed in the shop, and most people just followed the flow of people from the exit of the ride through the shop to leave. Overall it was fun working at a new location and new ways to interact with the guests.</p>]]><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/09/droid-factory.jpg" alt="Droid Factory inside of Tatooine Traders"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/09/build-your-own-lightsaber.jpg" alt="Build your own lightsaber inside of Tatooine Traders"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/09/tatooine-traders-costume.jpg" alt="Tatooine Traders costume"/></content>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Working at Mouse Gear</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/mouse-gear"/>
<id>https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/mouse-gear</id>
<published>2016-10-01T00:00:00Z</published>
<updated>2016-10-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
<category term="dcp16"/><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last night I completed my goal of working in all four parks when I picked up a shift at Mouse Gears in Epcot. After I clocked in and was given a tour of Mouse Gears, I was put on tasking because there were too many cast members for me to be assigned to a register. I helped put back items that guest brought to the registers but decided not to purchase. Mouse Gears has a wide variety of merchandise, similar to the Emporium, but Mouse Gears also has food and Wine merchandise. Mouse Gears was very busy because Mickey's Not So Scary was happening at Magic Kingdom, so guests who did not have a party ticket came over to Epcot. Food and Wine was also happening, which draws large crowds. It also rained most of the night, which caused guest to seek shelter in the shop. Once I was assigned to a register, then night went by faster and it was enjoyable. There was almost always a line at all of the registers. The shift I picked up was a closing shift, so once Mouse Gears closed, I helped with putbacks and stocking and making everything neat and organized. It was very interesting working at Epcot, backstage is completely different than Studios or Magic Kingdom. I'm not sure if I will pick up any more shifts in Epcot. My next goal is to work in every land of the Magic Kingdom. I have already worked Liberty Square, New Fantasyland/Storybook Circus, and Main Street.</p>]]><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/10/mousegear.jpg" alt="Mouse Gear costume"/></content>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>The Main Street Electrical Parade final performance</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/msep-final-performance"/>
<id>https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/msep-final-performance</id>
<published>2016-10-10T00:00:00Z</published>
<updated>2016-10-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
<category term="dcp16"/><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last night the Main Street Electrical Parade performed its last show. The Electrical Parade is one of my favorite parades, right behind Spectromagic and Boo To You. The parade had 2 performances, 9pm and 11pm. I stayed to watch both, then followed the parade along the parade route until the end. The sides of the streets were packed with guests watching the parade at both 9pm and 11pm and the crowd following the last float till the end was massive. It was a very sad to watch the final performance, but it was fun following it along the route, clapping along with the other guests and singing the end of the song every time it finished. The Electrical Parade is now making its way over to Disneyland to say goodbye, which leaves Magic Kingdom without a nighttime parade for now.</p>]]><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/msep/01-tinkerbell.jpg" alt="Tinkerbell"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/msep/02-train.jpg" alt="Train"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/msep/03-train.jpg" alt="Train"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/msep/04-train.jpg" alt="Train"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/msep/05-train.jpg" alt="Train"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/msep/06-train.jpg" alt="Train"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/msep/07-train.jpg" alt="Train"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/msep/08-turtle.jpg" alt="Turtle"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/msep/09-turtle.jpg" alt="Turtle"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/msep/10-turtle.jpg" alt="Turtle"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/msep/11-turtle.jpg" alt="Turtle"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/msep/12-cat.jpg" alt="Cheshire Cat"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/msep/13-mice.jpg" alt="Cinderella"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/msep/14-cinderella.jpg" alt="Cinderella"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/msep/15-cinderella.jpg" alt="Cinderella"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/msep/16-cinderella.jpg" alt="Cinderella"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/msep/17-cinderella.jpg" alt="Cinderella"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/msep/18-cinderella.jpg" alt="Cinderella"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/msep/19-cinderella.jpg" alt="Cinderella"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/msep/20-pan.jpg" alt="Peter Pan"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/msep/21-pan.jpg" alt="Peter Pan"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/msep/22-pan.jpg" alt="Peter Pan"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/msep/23-seven.jpg" alt="Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/msep/24-seven.jpg" alt="Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/msep/25-pine.jpg" alt="Pinocchio"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/msep/26-pine.jpg" alt="Pinocchio"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/msep/27-pine.jpg" alt="Pinocchio"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/msep/28-dragon.jpg" alt="Elliott from Pete's Dragon"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/msep/29-dragon.jpg" alt="Elliott from Pete's Dragon"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/msep/30-dragon.jpg" alt="Elliott from Pete's Dragon"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/msep/31-dragon.jpg" alt="Elliott from Pete's Dragon"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/msep/32-dragon.jpg" alt="Elliott from Pete's Dragon"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/msep/33-dragon.jpg" alt="Elliott from Pete's Dragon"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/msep/34-dragon.jpg" alt="Elliott from Pete's Dragon"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/msep/35-dragon.jpg" alt="Elliott from Pete's Dragon"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/msep/36-end.jpg" alt=""/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/msep/37-end.jpg" alt=""/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/msep/38-end.jpg" alt=""/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/msep/39-end.jpg" alt=""/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/msep/40-end.jpg" alt=""/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/msep/41-end.jpg" alt=""/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/msep/42-end.jpg" alt=""/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/msep/43-end.jpg" alt=""/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/msep/44-end.jpg" alt=""/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/msep/45-end.jpg" alt=""/></content>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Working in Dinoland</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/dinoland"/>
<id>https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/dinoland</id>
<published>2016-10-20T00:00:00Z</published>
<updated>2016-10-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
<category term="dcp16"/><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently picked up a shift in Dinoland in Animal Kingdom. Dinoland's shop is a decent size and is themed like a roadside attraction. The shop was a bit slow that day because Dinosaur was still down for refurbishment so less guests were in Dinoland, and guests were not exiting the ride through the gift shop. I went back and forth from register to greeting guests in the shop and pin trading. Dinoland has several outdoor carts and I worked two of them. The first cart was the Nemo cart over by the exit of Finding Nemo the Musical. Every 45 minutes, the theater would empty and the Nemo cart would get busy for a few minutes, then it would die down. The other cart I worked was the cart by the entrance of Dinoland. I didn't really sell anything or interact with many guests, but I was only out at the cart 5 minutes before I clocked out. The cart was one of the Wilderness Explorer stops, so it was fun to help kids with the Wilderness Explorers badge. For the badge at the Dino cart, wilderness Explorers had to find three signal flags near the entrance of Dinoland, but since I was only at the cart for about 5 minutes, I was only able to help one family with the Wildernss Explorer badge. Its always fun working in Animal Kingdom, it just seems completely different from the shops at the other parks.</p>]]><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/10/dinoland.jpg" alt="Dinorama costume"/></content>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Working Mickey's Not So Scary Halloween Party</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/working-mnsshp"/>
<id>https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/working-mnsshp</id>
<published>2016-11-01T00:00:00Z</published>
<updated>2016-11-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
<category term="dcp16"/><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Mickey's Not So Scary Halloween party is my favorite thing to do at Disney World. I went to the party as a guest the second week of September. This year I also had the opportunity to pick up shifts in Magic Kingdom during the parties.</p><p>The first Halloween party shift I picked up was at the Emporium. The Emporium was slower than usual because less tickets are sold for the parties than normal days and because most of the guests were outside enjoying all of the party exclusive offerings throughout the park. I started my shift in the Star Wars/Pixar/snacks section. We also had one of the party exclusive trading pins and the Halloween ornaments. Working in this section was really fun and enjoyable because there was Halloween music playing in the first few sections of the Emporium. I then went to the Princess section, which was playing the Kidz Bop Halloween album all night. The Princess section is one of the slower sections of the Emporium, but I was able to listen to the Boo TO You parade and the Happy Hallowishes fireworks, which are both amazing. My last position of the night was in the Mickey/Minnie section, which is where most of the Halloween merchandise is. We also had the annual passholder exclusive shirt a the register. I ended up picking up 2 more party shifts at the Emporium that went about the same a the first shift.</p><p>The second Halloween party shift I picked up was a treats shift. The location I picked up was in Pete's Silly Side Show in Storybook Circus. Picking up a treats shift is very difficult because most of them are given to attraction cast members and then some are post for cast members looking for extra hours around 3 am on Sunday. I was able to pick up the shift from a cast member on Facebook. I had never worked in Storybook Circus before, so it was funny to work a candy shift there before working a merchandise shift. The treats shift was so much fun, probably one of my favorite shifts I have worked. Handing out candy to guests for 6 hours, the phrase "Happy Halloween" started to sound like nonsense words after saying it to every guest who comes through the candy line. On my break I was able to watch Hallowishes from behind Pete's Silly Sideshow, which is an amazing view of the fireworks. My favorite moment of the night was when a group of guests came in with there service dogs who were dressed up in costumes and trick or treating for their owners. They held the treat bags in there mouth and walked up to us to get the candy. It was the cutest and most amazing thing I have ever seen working for Disney.</p><p>I also picked up a couple of shifts at Big Top Souvenirs. Big Top is a popular shop during the Halloween parties because the treat location at Pete's Silly sideshow exits into Big Top, and it is also the only shop that has all of the party exclusive pins. The first shift I picked up at Big Top I was on the same register all night because it was the only register that didn't need special training. On party night, there are too many cast members working in Big Top, so I was often put on games to entertain the guests such as ring toss or “pin the boo on the ghost”. I also helped handed out samples from the candy counter.</p><p>I traded one of my Fantasmic shifts for a glow cart shift in Magic Kingdom. My cart was in Liberty Square right on the corner of the parade route. Magic Kingdom's glow carts are several times larger than the glow carts we have at Fantasmic. For example we only take 10 sorcerer glow swords at Fantasmic, Magic kingdom takes 50 swords; we take 24 bubbles (12 Ariel bubbles and 12 blue bubbles), Magic Kingdom takes 24 of each. At Fantasmic we recently got tablets for all the carts which has doubled our sales; Magic Kingdom does not yet have tablets, but yet still makes more money per cart than we do with tablets. The glow shifts at Magic Kingdom are also longer than Fantasmic shifts. Working the glow cart during the party was so much fun. I got to listen to Haunted Mansion music all night long, got to see tons of awesome costumes, was able to watch Boo-to-You and Hallowishes, and got to wear the Halloween costume.</p><p>Another location I worked on a party night was the Pirates gift shop. It was slow during the party since most guests are not riding rides and mostly go to Emporium or Circus for the Halloween party merchandise, so I was greeting guests as they came off of the ride more than being on a register. It was a fun location to work. I got to listen to the Pirates music before the party started, then once the party started Adventureland played adventure-themed rock music such as Rock You Like a Hurricane or Message in a Bottle. Since the Pirates gift shop is very open, almost an outdoor location, I was able to watch Hallowishes. I had picked up a closing shift, so after the ride was clear of guests I help straighten and restock the shop.</p><p>Hurricane Mathew forced Disney to cancel 2 Halloween parties. I had picked up shifts for both parties that were canceled. One of the shifts was Frontierland, which I had never worked before, so I was very disappointed when I did not get to work the shift. Luckily I was able to find another party shift in Frontierland before Halloween was over. I worked the Trading post and Big Als, the outdoor cart. I love pin trading, so working at the Trading Post was a ton of fun. It was slow during the party, but that gave me a chance to really interact with the guests and do a lot of pin trading. I was assigned to Big Als about an hour before the first parade. I got to listen to the Cadaver Dans, the undead cowboy barbershop quartet. I was able to watch Boo-to-You from the cart which was an amazing view. I was moved back into the Trading Post, but since it was a slow night I was also able to watch Hallowishes from the door.</p><p>I ended the Halloween season with another treats shift at Pete's Silly sideshow. This shift was even more fun and enjoyable than the last treats shift. I was able to watch Hallowishes for the last time of the year. The costumes on Halloween were some of the best costumes I have seen this year. One guest was carrying an Eggo waffles box which confused me at first, but then I realized she was Eleven from the show Stranger Things. There were a few groups of guests dressed as the stretching portrait characters from the Haunted Mansion. My favorite costume of the night was a guest dressed as Hank from Finding Dory and was carrying a coffee pot with Dory swimming in it. Since it was the last Halloween Party, we were encouraged to give generous amounts of candy to the guests to get rid of it all. We ended up pre-filling candy bags and handing them to the guests, filling every bag they had, even filling popcorn buckets/backpacks/merchandise bags. After midnight, we jokingly wished the guests a Merry Christmas since the Halloween season at Disney had ended and they parks were already switching decorations over to Christmas that night after park clear.</p>]]><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/09/treats-group.jpg" alt="Treats group photo"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/11/halloween-party-costume.jpg" alt="Halloween Party costume"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/10/circus-costume.jpg" alt="Storybook Circus costume"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/10/pirates.jpg" alt="Pirates costume"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/11/fronteirland-costume.jpg" alt="Fronteirland mercandise costume"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/11/2016-MNSS-group.jpg" alt="Treats group photo"/></content>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Working at Disney Springs</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/disney-springs"/>
<id>https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/disney-springs</id>
<published>2016-12-06T00:00:00Z</published>
<updated>2016-12-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
<category term="dcp16"/><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After working in all 4 parks, I wanted to pick up shifts in Disney Springs. The first location I picked up was World of Disney, one of the largest Disney stores in the world. I thought since I enjoyed working at the Emporium that working at World of Disney would be about the same experience. I was wrong. World of Disney is so much busier than Emporium. I was on register all night long and the line of guests did not stop until after the store closed. I was in the Enchanted Dinning Room, a bank of registers that have the themeing of the dinning room from Beauty and the Beast, all night long. After we closed I helped straighten the plush toys in one of the largest plush toy sections of any Disney store. Working at World of Disney was stressful but interesting and I probably will not be picking up there again.</p><p>I also picked up at the Christmas shop, Disney Day's of Christmas. This shift was not a busy as World of Disney, but was still very busy. I always get stressed when ringing up and wrapping fragile items, so ring up fragile ornaments all night long was not the most enjoyable shift, especially when the guests buys 7 ornaments and you have to wrap them all and try not to let the line of guest get too long. I enjoyed the Christmas shop more than World of Disney though. Listening to Christmas music all night was enjoyable and the night went pretty smooth once I got used to wrapping all the ornaments. I was on register all night long and clocked out before the store closed, so I never was tasking or restocking. This is another location that I will probably not be picking up at again.</p><p>Another shop I picked up was at the Star Wars Galactic Outpost over on the other side of Disney Springs. It was a pretty slow night, but it was a lot of fun. I got to merchantain the $170 lightsabers, help guests with the build-your-own lightsabers, and look at all the cool Star Wars artwork that is sold in the store. One unusual thing about the Star Wars Galactic Outpost is that their break room is Located on the second floor of Disney Quest, which is several buildings away and the only way to get from the Star Wars shop to the Disney Quest break room is onstage. I found out that we were able to just take off our name tag and just go to anywhere in Disney Springs, like to Starbucks which is just across from the Star Wars shop, but I already had all of my stuff in the Disney Quest break room, so I just went there.</p><p>The next week I picked up next door at the Superhero Headquarters. This was probably my favorite shop to work in Disney Springs. It is one of the smallest shops in Disney Springs, and the night was pretty slow, but I got to interact with the guests all night and merchantain Thor's hammer and Baby Groot. The other cast members working that night were awesome and we all had a lot of fun. I was able to watch the new Christmas drone show, which is really cool. My favorite guest interaction of the night was a guest who bought a vinylmation, opened it at the register, and when it wasn't the one he wanted, immediately bought another one and told the other cast member at the register that she couldn't look because she was bad luck. The second one he bought wasn't much better, so he went and bought a third one from a different set. While the guest didn't get any of the ones he wanted, he was still in a good mood when he left, and everyone working was also in a great mode from the interesting interaction. This time I didn;t bring anything with me so I didn't have to use the break room in Disney Quest and just went to Starbucks during my break, which was quite enjoyable. After the store closed, we didn't have much to do since the store was so slow that we straightened and restocked the store all night, so it was practically perfect when we closed. I want to pick up more shifts here again, but I don't have that much time before my program ends on January 5th, so I'm not sure if I will get a chance to work here again.</p>]]><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/12/worldofdisney.jpg" alt="World of Disney costume"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/12/IMG_20161117_204601.jpg" alt="Disney Day's of Christmas costume"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/12/Star-Wars-Galatic-Outpost.jpg" alt="Star Wars Galactic Outpost costume"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/12/Superhero-Headquarters.jpg" alt="Superhero Headquarters costume"/></content>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Working Mickey's Very Merry Christmas Party</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/working-mvmcp"/>
<id>https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/working-mvmcp</id>
<published>2016-12-25T00:00:00Z</published>
<updated>2016-12-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
<category term="dcp16"/><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After working many Halloween party shifts and enjoying them, I knew I wanted to work during Mickey's Very Merry Christmas Party.</p><p>The first Christmas party shift I picked up was a wristband distribution shift at the park entrance. The shift was very easy and very enjoyable. The Christmas parties start at 7pm, but guests going to the party can enter the park at 4pm. The entrance is split into two: guests going to the party and normal day guests. As the party guests entered, I put a wristband on their wrist and wished them a Merry Christmas or told them to enjoy the party or some other greeting. I did that for 4 hours, that was the only thing I did the entire night. Even though it was extremely repettitive, it was still enjoyable because all of the cast members and all the guests were cheerful. I got to listen to Christmas music the entire shift and never ran into a problem or uncomfortable moment. The shift was only four hours long and I had time after the shift to go over to Disney Springs to watch Doctor Strange. I wanted to pick up another wristband shift, but was unable to find another shift.</p><p>Working towards my goal of working in as many shops I can, I picked up my first shift in Fantasyland. I worked in zone 2 which includes Fantasy Faire, the gift shop for Mickey's PhilharMagic, Sir Mickey's, which is the gift shop for the Princess Fairytale Hall. It was a very slow night, which most shops are slow during the parties, but this was probably one of the slowest shift I have worked. One thing I look forwards to when working the parties is the music in the shops switch over to holiday music once the parties start, but Fantasyland did not, which was disappointing. I only had a handful of transactions for the night and was mostly standing by waiting for guests to enter the shops. The shops were already stocked and organized since so few guest where there, so there was little to do.</p><p>Another new location I picked up during a party was Main Street East zone 3, which is the shop on the opposite site of Main Street from the Emporium. The first shop I was assigned to was Curtain Call Collectibles, which is the gift shop for Mickey's and Tinkerbell's Meet and Greet. It was slow, but the themeing in the shop is based around backstage of a Magician show which was really cool to look at all of the props and displays. The shops in Main Street zone three did not switch over to holiday music either, but the music wasn't bad. Another shop I worked in zone three was The Chapeau, which has a large selection of ears, bows, and other Disney hats. Guest can also get the hats embroidered there. The Chapeau has a great view of Main Street and I was able to watch the Christmas parade, which was cool.  I also worked at one of the outdoor carts near the train station. I mostly sold Mickey Santa hats and bulb necklaces as guests entered the park. One awesome thing about Main Street during the holidays is that Disney makes it snow, which was fun working in the snow without having to be freezing cold.</p><p>I picked up a shift at the Emporium, which is still one of my favorite shops to work. Working in the Emporium during the holidays is fun because there is a ton of Christmas ordainment and merchandise. There wasn't really much else different than any of the other shifts I picked up at the Emporium. After we closed I helped put away the Christmas Party exclusive merchandise and put the regular merchandise back out, which I had never done before and was interesting.</p><p>I picked up 2 shifts in Tomorrowland as was able to work in both zone 1 and zone 2. Tomorrowland plays TSO, Mannheim Steamroller, and other rock Christmas music during the parties, which is a fun change from the generic Christmas music that plays in all of the parks. Zone 1 is a lot slower than zone 2, mainly because no of the shop are attraction gift shops. I worked in the Buzz Lightyear gift shop for the first time, which was fun but very slow since the shop is so small most guests just walk through to the exit.</p><p>I was able to pick up a glow shift during one of the last Christmas parties which was my favorite Christmas party shift. My glow cart was located in Fronteirland, so I got to listen to country Christmas music once the party started. I got to wear the Christmas costume again, which was fun, and I had fun the entire shift. I was able to watch the Christmas parade again and had the best view of any shift I have worked.</p><p>Unlike the Halloween parties, there was not a Christmas party on Christmas, so I ended up working at Tower of Terror on Christmas. I only worked 8 Christmas parties and did not get to see parade/fireworks as much as I did during Halloween parties. I like the Halloween parties better, both as a guest and as a cast member, but the Christmas parties were still fun.</p>]]><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/11/christmas-party-costume.jpg" alt="Christmas Party costume"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/12/fantasyland.jpg" alt="Fantasyland costume"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/12/emporium.jpg" alt="Main Street costume"/></content>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Working at Memento Mori</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/memento-mori"/>
<id>https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/memento-mori</id>
<published>2016-12-27T00:00:00Z</published>
<updated>2016-12-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
<category term="dcp16"/><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I finally was able to pick up a shift at Memento Mori, Haunted Mansions gift shop. It is very difficult to find shifts at Memento Mori and whenever a shift was posted before, I was unable to pick it up because I was already working somewhere else, but last week I finally found one I could work. When I went to pick up the costume, I found out it was next to the Haunted Mansion attractions costume and when I clocked in I found out I was wearing the attractions shirt instead of the merchandise shirt. Luckily they are similar enough that it didn't matter that I was wearing the wrong shirt, but I felt weird the entire shift knowing I had the wrong shirt on.</p><p>Memento Mori is a smaller shop with not too much merchandise inside, so the shop was never really busy. There would always be guests inside the shop, but not many transactions and it was never packed. The shop only has three registers, so they don't need many cast members working the shop. One unique thing that Memento Mori has is a photo booth that can turn you into a ghost, with a photo that changes from your mortal state to ghost and back. The photo process is done by photopass cast members, but we take care of the transactions and giving the photos to the guest. Whenever a photo is ready, a bell rings to let you know that the photo has materialized inside of the photo cabinet which we then unlock for the guests. It was fun unlocking the cabinet to give the guests their ghost photos. Since it was Christmas week, the Christmas parade and fireworks were performed daily. I got to see the parade from afar and was able to listen to the Christmas fireworks one last time. Overall it was a fun location to work and I'm glad that I got to work at Memento Mori before my college program ended.</p>]]><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/12/mementomori.jpg" alt="Memento Mori costume"/></content>
</entry>
