<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:fh="http://purl.org/syndication/history/1.0" xml:base="/feed.atom" xml:lang="en">
<title>My Adventure Blog</title>
<id>https://ryanmontville.com/disney/</id>
<link rel="alternate" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/"/>
<link rel="hub" href="https://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/"/>
<link rel="self" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/feed-0.atom"/>
<link rel="first" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/feed-0.atom"/>
<link rel="prev-archive" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/feed-1.atom"/>
<link rel="current" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/feed-2.atom"/>
<link rel="next" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/feed-3.atom"/>
<link rel="last" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/feed-4.atom"/>
<updated>2025-05-16T23:04:16-04:00</updated>
<author>
<name>Ryan Montville</name>
</author>
<entry>
<title>Week 8</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/week-8"/>
<id>https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/week-8</id>
<published>2015-03-14T00:00:00Z</published>
<updated>2015-03-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
<category term="dcp15"/><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sunday and Monday I worked from open to close. Tuesday I was sick again. Wednesday I went to the Flower and Garden Festival at Epcot, which was awesome. The festival started last week and will go on until May 17. The festival has brought extra flowers and sculptures to the park, along with several new food locations and activities around the park. After Epcot I went to Magic Kingdom for a few hours. Thursday, Friday, and Saturday I worked from open to close, which means I worked 52 hours this week.</p>]]><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/03/marf01.jpg" alt="Tick-Tock from Peter Pan"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/03/marf11.jpg" alt="Mufasa, Rafiki, Simba, and Nala from The Lion King"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/03/marf05.jpg" alt="Cogsworth and Lumiere from Beauty and the Beast"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/03/marf04.jpg" alt="Belle and Beast from Beauty and the Beast"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/03/marf19.jpg" alt="Pluto and Daisy"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/03/marf06.jpg" alt="Lumiere and Cogsworth from Beauty and the Beast"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/03/marf12.jpg" alt="Timon and Pumbaa from The Lion King"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/03/marf10.jpg" alt="Snow White and the 7 dwarfs"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/03/marf09.jpg" alt="Woody from Toy Story"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/03/marf18.jpg" alt="Donald, Chip, and Dale"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/03/marf03.jpg" alt="Cinderella and Prince Charming"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/03/marf13.jpg" alt="Phineas and Ferb"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/03/marf14.jpg" alt="Mater from Cars"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/03/marf15.jpg" alt="Lightning McQueen from Cars"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/03/marf16.jpg" alt="Buzz Lightyear from Toy Story"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/03/marf17.jpg" alt="Sorcerer Mickey from Fantasia"/></content>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Day 65: PAC</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/day-65"/>
<id>https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/day-65</id>
<published>2015-03-24T00:00:00Z</published>
<updated>2015-03-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
<category term="dcp15"/><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I picked up a Parade Audience Control (PAC) shift at the Magic Kingdom. Cast members have the opportunity to pick up open shifts at other locations and one of the shifts available to work is the parades. The main responsibilities of PAC shifts include directing guests, keeping the walkways clear, and telling guest where the can and cannot go. I clocked in a 7pm backstage and was assigned to a captain along with four other cast members. We where assigned to the garden walkway in the newly expanded hub area in front of the castle. Our job included keeping guest inside of the parade/firework viewing area, keeping the walkway clear and make sure that the flow of guest keeps going the right way. Our walkway was a one-way walkway which had an intersection which lead to a shortcut to the main entrance that bypasses Main Street. I worked from 7-10:45pm through the first Electrical Parade, Celebrate the Magic, and Wishes. Tonight had cool weather and the park was not too crowded, which made the night stress-free and enjoyable. I will definitely try to pick up more PAC shifts in the future.</p><p>Other things that have happened recently:</p><p>- I went to a resume writing course that the Disney College Program offers. In the course I learned what Disney recruiters are looking for in a resume and how to improve my chances of getting noticed by Disney recruiters.</p><p>- We got new carpet last week, it is a bit better than the old carpet.</p><p>- My roommates and I conquered the mountains (Space Mountain, Splash Mountain, and Big Thunder Mountain) in the same day.</p>]]></content>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>100 days in the Disney College Program</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/day-100"/>
<id>https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/day-100</id>
<published>2015-04-28T00:00:00Z</published>
<updated>2015-04-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
<category term="dcp15"/><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today marks the 100th day of my Disney College Program. I am currently on the Disney cruise aboard the Disney Wonder with my roommates. I will post more about the cruise once we get back on May 1.</p><p>A lot has happened since I posted last and I have been very busy. March 29 through April 11 was spring break for most schools, which meant it was peek season for Disney World. Columbia Harbor House opened an hour earlier and closed and hour later than normal. I worked a total of 117 those two week, making it the most hours I have worked yet, and two of the largest pay checks I have gotten from Disney. Last week I was trained on register, which was two days of training. I enjoy being on the register, it might even be my favorite position at the Harbor House.</p><p>After 100 days in the Disney College Program, I am still loving it here in Orlando. While my job might not be fun or enjoyable 100% of the time, the memories I get to make for the guests and the adventures I have on my days off always make up for it. Everything about the program is perfect. I get along with my roommates all the time, our apartment is great, the weather is Florida is amazing, and being able to go to the parks whenever I want still hasn't gotten old.</p><p>Working for Disney has not ruined the magic for me. Working here, being able to see how Disney operates and makes the magic for all of the guests that visit the parks each day, has only made me love Disney more. Watching the parades and shows are still as fun as the first time I saw them. I am still learning new facts about Disney and trying new things everyday.</p><p>There are many days left until July 30 when my program ends and hopefully many more adventures left as well.</p>]]><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/01/apr100.jpg" alt="100 days in the DCP!"/></content>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Day 104: Disney Wonder</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/day-104"/>
<id>https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/day-104</id>
<published>2015-05-02T00:00:00Z</published>
<updated>2015-05-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
<category term="dcp15"/><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I went on the Disney wonder with my roommates April 26-May 1. We sailed to Cozumel and Castaway Cay, Disney private island. The cruise was a ton of fun and I am glad I was able to go on it with my roommates.</p><p>We did too many things on the cruise to list, so here are the highlights of the cruise.</p><p>Each night the theater put on a show. My favorite of the shows was Toy Story the musical, which was a musical adaptation of the first movie. It had all of the characters, most of which you don't see in the parks.</p><p>The first stop was Cozumel. We decided to go to Chankanaab national park. We swam with the dolphins, swam in the ocean, watched a sea lion show, and relaxed on the beach. That night's show was Kyle & Mistie Knight's magic show, which was really cool. The next night they performed in the adult only lounge and I was chosen to be part of the show. Mistie did a quick change trick where she was tied up, then 30 seconds later was wearing my jacket. It was a lot of fun being part of the show. The next trick my roommates went up. Seven people were given envelopes, then an eighth person picked a random number from a phone book, then it was revealed that the envelopes had the numbers in the phone number, in the correct order.</p><p>The last day of the cruise we went to Disney's private island in the Bahamas, Castaway Cay. We did the Castaway 5k in the morning, the hung out on the beach for the rest of the day. The cruise had a midnight showing of the Avengers 2 that night.</p>]]><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/05/mayc12.jpg" alt="OVerlooking Castaway Cay"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/05/mayc01.jpg" alt="Pirates night"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/05/mayc02.jpg" alt="Disney Wonder"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/05/mayc03.jpg" alt="After running the Castaway Cay 5k"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/05/mayc04.jpg" alt="Cozumel"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/05/mayc05.jpg" alt="Pirates night"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/05/mayc06.jpg" alt="Toy Story musical"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/05/mayc07.jpg" alt="Pirates night"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/05/mayc23.jpg" alt="Castaway Cay"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/05/mayc08.jpg" alt="Pirates night"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/05/mayc09.jpg" alt="Disney Wonder"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/05/mayc10.jpg" alt="Cozumel"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/05/mayc11.jpg" alt="Castaway Cay"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/05/mayc13.jpg" alt="Animator's Palate"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/05/mayc14.jpg" alt="Pirates night"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/05/mayc15.jpg" alt="Cozumel"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/05/mayc16.jpg" alt="Disney Wonder"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/05/mayc17.jpg" alt="Pirates night"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/05/mayc18.jpg" alt="Disney Wonder"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/05/mayc19.jpg" alt="Disney Wonder"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/05/mayc20.jpg" alt="Magic show"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/05/mayc24.jpg" alt="Castaway Cay"/></content>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Day 164: BIRTHDAY!</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/day-164"/>
<id>https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/day-164</id>
<published>2015-07-01T00:00:00Z</published>
<updated>2015-07-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
<category term="dcp15"/><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today is my 23rd birthday. It is also Jen, one of my co-worker's, birthday. We celebrated by going horseback riding at Fort Wilderness, which was a lot of fun. My horse, cooper, was awesome and made the ride a lot of fun. We went to go eat at Trails End afterwards, which was delicious. After Trails End we went to Magic Kingdom. We got birthday buttons, stopped by work, rode Haunted Mansion, went to the Laugh Floor, and hung out for a while. It started raining so all of the night show were cancelled, but we still had fun in the rain. We hung out in the Main Street shops for a bit before heading home. This was definitely one the best birthdays I have ever had, and I'm glad I got to spend it in Disney World with my Friends.</p><p>Other stuff that has happened since my last post:</p><p>- Alex did not extend with us, so his program ended on May 15.</p><p>- Magic Kingdom was open for 24 hours to kick off Disney's coolest summer ever. Columbia Harbor House was open until 2 am and I worked until 3 am. It was fun working later than normal. We were not too busy, the guest were all very nice, and closing went by quickly.</p><p>- I went kayaking with some of my friends at Shingle Creek.</p><p>- Magic Kingdom was rented out by IPW, an international travel company. The park closed a 6 pm to guest. We were the only location to stay open and serve our normal menu during the event. A few other locations had buffets.</p><p>- Star Wars weekends happened at Hollywood Studios. The Backlots tour, which recently shut down, turned into Darth's Mall, which consisted of two stores filled with Star War's merchandise. There were also character meet and greets. I had the chance to meet some clone troopers, chewbacca, and Chip and Dale as ewoks.</p><p>- My family came down to visit for a second time.</p>]]><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/07/julyk1.jpg" alt="Shingle Creek"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/07/julyk2.jpg" alt="Shingle Creek"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/07/julyk3.jpg" alt="Shingle Creek"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/07/julybd3.png" alt="Birthday celebration at M.K."/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/07/maysww.jpg" alt="Chip and Dale Ewoks at Star Wars Weekends"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/07/julybd2.png" alt="Tomorrowland"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2015/07/julyfam.jpg" alt="Hanging out with my family"/></content>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Day 193: Driving home</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/day-193"/>
<id>https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/day-193</id>
<published>2015-07-30T00:00:00Z</published>
<updated>2015-07-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
<category term="dcp15"/><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My Disney College Program has come to an end and I am driving home today with my siblings. My car's transmission had some internal failure and was going to cost $4,000 to fix it, so I had it towed and left it in Florida. I drove my parent's car home.</p>]]><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/01/julydriving.jpg" alt="Driving home with my sibs"/></content>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>The End (of my Disney College Program)</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/the-end"/>
<id>https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/the-end</id>
<published>2015-07-31T00:00:00Z</published>
<updated>2015-07-31T00:00:00Z</updated>
<category term="dcp15"/><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My Disney College Program is over and I'm back in Ohio. The program has been one of the best experiences of my life. I had a ton of fun, meet new friends from all over the world, learned new skills, and made lots of memories I will never forget. Working for Disney has definitely been the best job I have ever had. The magic of Disney has not been ruined for me, learning how Disney works and getting to make the guests happy has only made me love Disney more.</p><p>My siblings flew down on the 28. We did all four parks in one day on the 29. We started at Animal Kingdom, then over to Hollywood Studios, then to Epcot, and ended in Magic Kingdom and stayed until park close at 1 am. We spent the night at the Animal Kingdom Lodge and then started the 2 day drive back to Ohio the next morning.</p><p>Even though my program is over, this is not goodbye to Disney, just see ya real soon. I go back to school for my final year in August, and hope to graduate in May and go back to Disney for a professional internship. I will continue to update this blog every once in a while when new things happen. Thanks for reading!</p>]]><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/01/julyfpod.png" alt="Four parks, one day"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/01/julygrad.jpg" alt="DCP graduation"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/01/julygrad2.jpg" alt="DCP graduation"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/01/julygroup.jpg" alt="Roommate group photo"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/01/julyrock.jpg" alt="Rock 'n' Rollercoaster"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/01/july3a.jpg" alt="The Three Caballeros"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/01/aprbeach.jpg" alt="Hanging out at the beach"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/01/julygroup2.jpg" alt="Roommate group photo"/></content>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Mickey's Not So Scary Halloween Party</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/not-so-scary"/>
<id>https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/not-so-scary</id>
<published>2015-10-20T00:00:00Z</published>
<updated>2015-10-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
<category term=""/><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I went back to Disney World during OSU's fall break with my family. I flew in on Thursday and stayed at my friend's apartment Thursday and Friday. On Thursday we went to Splitsville and walked around Disney Springs as well. On Friday we went to Mickey's not so scary Halloween party. The party didn't start until 7 pm, but the ticket allows you to get into Magic Kingdom at 4 pm. The Halloween parties are one of the few times where you can wear costumes to Disney World. I went as Mrs. Nesbitt. We rode a few ride, then had dinner at Be Our Guest, which was my first time eating there. Once the party started, we focused more on the party exclusive things rather than riding rides, since we can ride them whenever we want. We got to meet Lotso, which you can only meet during special events, which was really fun. We went and watched the new Hocus Pocus Villain Spelltacular, which was one of the best show Disney has ever produced. We stayed and watched Celebrate the magic and Hallowishes. We walked around and checked out all of the decorations throughout the park while we waited for the Boo To You parade. Boo to You is my new favorite nighttime entertainment at Disney World. After the parade we rode Big Thunder Mountain, then trick-or-treated throughout the park until park close.</p><p>The rest of my family flew in on Saturday and we stayed at the Tree House Villas for the rest of our vacation. We went to Disney Springs Saturday night. Sunday we went to Universal Studios and I went to the Halloween party again with my family. My parents dressed as Fear and Joy from Inside out. My sister went as Anger, my brothers went as Christopher Robin and Dipper from Gravity Falls, and my grandpa went as grown up Russell from Up. We went on rides, saw the show, and got to listen to the Cadaver Dans, the undead Dapper Dans. On Monday we went to Epcot in the morning and checked out the Food and Wine festival. My favorite time to go to Epcot is during the festivals because there is so much more to do throughout the world showcase and the rest of the park. We then park hopped over to the Magic Kingdom for the rest of the day. We rode the rides we didn't ride the day before and then watched Wishes and the Main Street Electric Light parade. My sister and I flew back to Columbus on Tuesday because we had to go back to school. I already have my next trip planned for January before the spring semester starts.</p>]]><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/01/octh2.jpg" alt="The castle before Hocus Pocus Villain Spelltacular"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/01/octh3.jpg" alt="Lotso"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/01/octh4.png" alt="Lotso"/></content>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Working in Hollywood Hills</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/hollywood-hills"/>
<id>https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/hollywood-hills</id>
<published>2016-06-16T00:00:00Z</published>
<updated>2016-06-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
<category term="dcp16"/><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My second Disney College Program has started and I am all done with training at my new location at Hollywood Studios. I'm working in Hollywood Hills which includes Rock 'n' Roller Coaster, Tower of Terror, and Fantasmic. The first 2 weeks of program similar to my last program: checking in, Traditions, a few classes at Disney University. The Hollywood Studios orientation was a lot of fun. I enjoy learning about the history and stories of the parks and Hollywood Studios has a lot of awesome stories. Tower if Terror is one of my favorite rides and learning more about the story of the ride was really cool. I also learned that Tower and Coaster share some history. The Hollywood Tower hotel opened in 1917. G-Force Records opened in the 1920s. G-Force Records used the Hollywood Tower Hotel as a place for the artists and bands to stay when they were in town recording in the studios until lighting stuck the hotel on October 31, 1939. When Disney was building Walt Disney World, they purchased the Hollywood Tower Hotel for guest to stay at, but when they unlocked the doors, the bellhops appeared along with the rest of the hotel staff. Plans to reopen the hotel for guests to stay was scrapped.</p><p>Training at Coaster, Tower, and Fantasmic went well and went by quickly. I already had register experience from my last program at Columbia Harbour House. The costumes for my locations are nice and more comfortable than the Columbia Harbor House costume. I am really enjoying working in Hollywood Hills and right now my favorite location to work is at Fantasmic, although I have not yet worked a shift at Tower after training. Working merchandise is a lot of fun because part of the role is pin trading with guests or mechantaining the products such as having lightsaber duels with the guests.</p>]]><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/06/Coaster-costume.jpg" alt="Rock 'n' Rollercoaster merchandise costume"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/06/Fantasmic-costume.jpg" alt="Fantasmic merchandise costume"/><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/06/tower-costume.jpg" alt="Tower of Terror merchandise costume"/></content>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Working The Outpost Shop</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/outpost-shop"/>
<id>https://ryanmontville.com/disney/#/outpost-shop</id>
<published>2016-07-10T00:00:00Z</published>
<updated>2016-07-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
<category term="dcp16"/><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One goal I have for my second program is to work all four parks. Recently I was able to check off a second park, Animal Kingdom, when I worked at The Outpost Shop. The Outpost Shop is the shop and cart outside of Animal Kingdoms main entrance. The cart and shop are by the tram stop and the bus stop, so all of the guests going to Animal Kingdom pass by the shop before entering the park. The Outpost shop is small compared to Coaster or Tower, but I really liked the layout of the shop with the registers in the center of the shop and all of the merchandise surrounding it. Most of the purchases guests made at the shop and cart were hats, sunglasses, and bottles of water. Even though it was a slow day compared to working at Hollywood Hills, it was still a really enjoyable shift. I plan on picking up more shifts at new locations and try to work at as many locations as possible.</p>]]><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RyanMontville/disney/refs/heads/main/src/images/2016/07/Outpost.jpg" alt="Outpost shop costume"/></content>
</entry>
